# **About Me**

Full name: SON, DO HONG

City: Ho Chi Minh

Phone: (+84) 963-260-895
Email: hongsondhs@gmail.com

**Skype:** hongsondhs **Facebook:** fb.com/sondh5

Hello I'm Son Do. I am from Hanoi and now working in Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam.

I graduated from FPT University Hanoi. I started web development with Ruby on Rails from September 2016. My technology stack: Ruby/Ruby on Rails; MySQL/PostgreSQL; HTML/CSS/jQuery. I also have experience of setting up and building application with Amazon web services: S3, EC2, Cloudfront, Cloudwatch, etc. I would say that I am an extroverted, enthusiastic person and proud of my ability to persevere and overcome

challenges.



### Background



#### **Working History**

#### Web Developer - Zigexn VeNtura

Jan 2019 - Present

- Working in sharing economy product of company, team size 6 devs
- Shipping new features, bug-fixes in every 2-week sprint
- Using Apache Solr as search engine
- Run application with over million products
- Updating and importing list products everyday

# Web Developer - Framgia Inc.

Sep 2016 - Dec 2018

- Working in Digital Comics outsourcing project, teamsize ~30 devs
- Run product with over 2 million users (both web and native mobile app)
- Shipping new features, bug-fixes in every 2-week sprint
- Involved in building a system of 4 front servers, admin, batch, worker server
- Familiar with auto deployment with Capistrano or manually by running shell script
- Coding, review codes, improve CI/CD flow to collab with other teams
- Improve performance, have experiences in reading server log
- Develop project with Ruby on Rails as backend and other frontend related skills
- AWS products used: EC2, RDS, CloudWatch, S3, CloudFront, ELB, Route53 etc

#### Freelancer - Vinalign

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

- Working in freelance project with 3 devs
- Communicate directly with the customer to define the requirement from the customer's ideas
- Involved in building a web application from zero till service in
- Run product with ~150 clinics, ~450 patients
- Familiar with auto deployment with Capistrano or manually by running shell script
- Monitoring and maintaining during a year after official release

#### Intern - FPT Software

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Involved in short-term on job training at FSU11.F-1
- Team size: 8 devs
- Technologies: Java Spring MVC, AngularJS, HTML/CSS
- Accomplishments: coding, teamwork, software process

# Education History

#### Software Engineer Degree - FPT University

Sep 2013 - Dec 2017

- FPT University Talented full scholarship at Software Engineering
- Field of study: Software Engineering
- Degree rank: Good
- Certificate of completion Pearson Longman Level 6 Summit 2
- President at FU No Shy Club (English speaking and soft skill club)
- Activities and societies: English and soft skills club, Vovinam Club, Photography Club, Student council

#### High School Degree - Van Noi Highschool

Sep 2010 - May 2013

- Major: Maths, Physics, Chemistry
- Degree rank: Good
- Activities and societies: VN50 Team

T					•						•	П	П	
	<b>a</b>	~	n	n	П	•	3		C	v	П	п	ш	c
	Э.	ч	ш	ш	П	u	a	L	-		u	u	u	•

Ruby on Rails							
MySQL							
HTML/CSS							
Amazon Web Services (AWS)							
JavaScript/iQuery							

# Tools & Technologies

- ✓ Linux system (Ubuntu, macOS)
- ✓ Git version control (Github)
- ✓ Apache Solr
- ✓ Microsoft Office
- ✓ Adobe Photoshop

# Languages

- **✓** English
- ✓ Japanese

# **Recent Freelance Projects**









#### **Achivements**



# **Agile Fundamentals**

Certificate Issuing by ICAgile Issued Jan 2018



# Ruby on rails course

Certificate Issuing by Framgia Inc. Issued Oct 2016



# Top 5 Social Activity Contributor

Certificate Issuing by FPT University Issued Spring 2015 & Summer 2015



# Honor Student

Certificate Issuing by FPT University Issued Summer 2017